Benjamin Starostka Jakobsen

BSc. Software Technology · Engineering Student

Rævehøjvej 36, 1.1403 - Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

🛮 (+45) 60 47 07 15 | 🗷 benjamin.starostka@gmail.com | 🏕 starostka.substack.com | 🖸 starostka | 🛅 starostka

"Learning to enjoy reading and growing is the best thing that has ever happened to me."

Who am I?

A compassionate and creative student with academic experience in the field of computer science and years of developer experience within the IT industry. Great at English and an advocate of collaborative success. Passionate about human-interactions and the science behind AI, cognition and Data.

Education

DTU(Technical University of Denmark)

Denmark

BSc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2018 - Exp. Jul. 2021

- Writing my bachelor's in the use of deep learning to help diagnose diseases (Open Domain Question Answering). This work is done together
 with a research group from the Department of Cognitive Systems at DTU.
- · A part of Wall of PF for my effort on creating a mobile application and platform for the engineering students at DTU.

Experience

KMD Ballerup, Denmark

STUDENT DEVELOPER

Aug. 2019 - PRESENT

- Worked as a .NET developer on different services used by health clinics.
- As part of the Research & Development team I help innovate on a range of different solutions.
- Setup various application monitoring systems and CI/CD pipeline integrations.
- Deployed applications on Microsoft Azure and frequently help maintain services.
- Recently begun doing data analytics and being involved in machine-learning activities.

Polyteknisk Forening

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

Mar. 2019 - PRESENT

- SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & ARCHITECT
- · Currently building a mobile application using React Native and collaborating on building an information platform for the students at DTU.
- Implemented RESTful API server for the mobile application with support for GraphQL.
- Together with a design & innovation engineering student we make up the little team with high hopes for the project.

Cobham PLC. Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

STUDENT ASSISTANT

Aug. 2017 - Jun. 2019

- Worked on the Aviator S. project (Testing avionics) with Airbus as customer.
- Dealing with automating test systems.
- Worked with Linux & Docker containers.
- Used Python to create a lot of scripts.

Honors & Awards

DOMESTIC

2020 **Certificate**, ISO 21500 – Project Management (DS - Danish Standard)

Denmark

2019 Finalist, BEST case study (case study about environmental sustainability)

Microsoft Lyngby, Denmark

Polyteknisk

2013 **Wall of PF**, For the effort on building a mobile app for students at DTU.

Forening, Denmark

Writing_

A new substack newsletter I've yet to give a name

Substack

FOUNDER & WRITER

Feb. 2021 - PRESENT

• I would like to try and share my thoughts openly on topics that interests me. I see it as sort of a public journal and a great way to practice my writing skills.



Reading, Writing and doing Research I like to read and reflect a lot. And follow recent advancements through research.

Full Stack development

I know my way around backend and frontend technologies.

Music production Sometimes I like to record and compose music.

Motion graphics and Video editing

A hoppy that has enabled me to present content in an engaging fashion.

Volunteering Ex. the joy I feel working on an app to help my fellow students.

Functional training and Hiking I care about my health and like to enjoy the nature.